One thing I think is really important is that we often talk about values conflicts.
So someone might say I value my work, but I also value my home life or I value being productive,
but I also value being a collaborator. And we speak about these as if they in conflict,
as if they are adults with one another, that we can't reconcile them. And I think it's really
crucial to recognize that our values are not in conflict. Our values are never in conflict.
Our values just are. Our values are who we are and how we've evolved. And they aren't in conflict
with one another. Rather, what tends to be in conflict is our goals. It's not the values,
the goals that we have in relation to the values. For example, say you want to be at your child's
recital because you value family. And you also want to finish a work project with your team
because you value the sense of trust and collaboration that you have for one another.
Those values are beautiful and both of them can coexist. What you may need to figure out
is how you can manage your goals effectively. So for example, your goal of being at the child's
recital, you could go to it and yet you could explore different ways that you could use your time
and resources in order to finish the project with your team, say coming in early the next day.
And so it's not the values that are in conflict here. Rather, it is the goals. And the reality,
which is that human beings, we are messy and beautiful and we are not omnipotent and omnipresent.
We have limited time and limited resources. So instead of thinking that our values are in conflict,
it's helpful to recognize that it's our goals that are in conflict, that we can't be in two places
at the same time. And this is really helpful because it allows me to say, how can I be
present and connected with this current goal that I have? And then how can I bring myself towards
this other goal that is an expression of another value that I hold? And this is really liberating
because as human beings, we are always going to be faced with situations where there are goals
conflicts and it's helpful to focus on the goals themselves and how we can adjust and how we can
use our time and our resources effectively as opposed to berating ourselves or thinking that there's
something fundamentally wrong with us, that we've got a values conflict.